# **Steph Groat**

New York City, NY

https://github.com/StephGroat

steph.e.groat@gmail.com (734) 612-0186

# **SUMMARY**

Skilled backend engineer with a focus on the intersection of API development, back-end infrastructure development and dev ops. Experience in a wide variety of development environments ranging from military and government to fully remote startups.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Snackable AI New York, NY

Software Engineer

Nov 2019 – Present

- Designed and implemented (Node.js and TypeScript) the external facing API as well as the web app portal redesign.
- Developed consumer services (Python and Node.js) turning raw machine learning data into usable features.
- Expanded MySQL database models to support feature enhancements and data scalability.
- Integrated AWS messaging, monitoring and deployments to support the backend services.

# **SpareMin (now Headliner)**

New York, NY

Backend Developer Intern

June 2016 – August 2016

- Designed and implemented video generation services for recorded audio highlights in the app.
- Expanded the SQL database to support video generation services and provide templating for related expansions.
- Integrated social media platforms to provide easier accessibility of the video generation service.

# **Marine Corps Base Quantico**

Quantico, VA

Front-End Web Developer

November 2012 – August 2014

- Designed and built internal websites using JavaScript and provided tools for the end-user to create templated pages.
- Wrote, designed, and edited web page content and led a team to integrate the new tools into existing workflows.
- Conferred with senior government and military officials alongside the development team to prioritize the base's needs, develop content criteria and iterate through development of base workflow tools.
- Contributed inside the redesign team for websites under the Marines.mil domain

### SKILLS

Languages: Node.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Java, OCaml, Rust Frameworks & Tools: Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Git, Spring, Flask

### **EDUCATION**

Columbia University

New York, NY

B.A. Computer Science

October 2019

• Relevant Coursework: User Interface Design, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Graphics, Programming Languages & Translators, Databases